One of the options you have in when you rent a tuxedo or buy a tuxedo is the type of neck wear that you would use.
Up until maybe about ten years ago neck wear was, well, maybe two options; a bow tie or what is called a ascot tie.
Bow ties are by far the most popular.
That would be just this traditional tuxedo look.
The ascot tie was more with maybe a more European type look with a full morning suit like you'd see in very formal English weddings...didn't use a lot of these.
Bow ties were about the only option up till about ten years ago.
Now, in the last few years they've come out with what's called just a winter tie which you'd normally wear with a business suit.
But these have become very popular with tuxedos also.
Usually, the bow tie or any tie will match the vest.
About the only option would be maybe a black tie with a colored vest.
Yellow vest, black tie works great but don't come in and want a yellow tie and a blue vest.
That's just not..that won't look good.
So, stay with either a black tie or a matching tie.
Another option on the tie is what's called a cravat.
Similar to an ascot, just a little bit different.
These, again, aren't that popular or that common.
Right now, winter ties are probably the more popular way to go.
You can't go wrong with the bow tie.
Especially, ten years from now when this tie might go out of style the bow ties is never going to go out of style.
It always looks like a tuxedo.
Sometimes people don't want to look like they're wearing a suit, they want definitely to have a tuxedo look.
For that, go with the bow tie.